
    <rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" version="2.0">
      <channel>
        <title>Ezequiel Castellanos | Front End Web Developer</title>
        <link>http://ezecastellanos.com.ar</link>
        <description>Blog page for Ezequiel</description>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 Aug 2021 05:35:07 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="http://ezecastellanos.com.ar" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        
    <item>
      <guid>http://ezecastellanos.com.ar/posts/Color generator cfcc0c3c605643d7b26cb87fc6cefba7</guid>
      <title>Color Generator</title>
      <description>Use values.js package to generate color tints and shades</description>
      <link>http://ezecastellanos.com.ar/posts/Color generator cfcc0c3c605643d7b26cb87fc6cefba7</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Aug 2021 05:35:07 GMT</pubDate>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1>Color generator</h1>
<p>If you ever want to build a color generator app please don't try to reinvent the wheel. There are many npm packages to help and assist you and most importantly, save you a lot of time. Sometimes it can be good practice to write your own script but don't let it get too complicated.</p>
<p>I found an interesting package called <strong><a href="https://noeldelgado.github.io/values.js/">values.js</a></strong> that provides us with tints and shades of a given color. Before I discovered this package I was going crazy converting colors from HEX to RGB and later to HSL, wasting time when I could have done a simple google search for: "npm color shades and tints"</p>
<h2>Installation</h2>
<pre><code class="language-bash">npm install values.js --save
</code></pre>
<h2>Usage</h2>
<pre><code class="language-jsx">import Values from 'values.js';
let color = new Values('#aaa');

// Generate the tints and shades of the base color as specified by weight 10.
console.log(color.all(10));
</code></pre>
<p>For my case of the Color Generator, I needed 10 tints (lighter) and 10 shades (darker). The all() method returns an array of color objects. Each object contains several useful properties such as weight, type, and rgbString, but for this particular case, I used the hex string to extract the HEX color code and the weight to represent the percentage of light/darkness.</p>
<p><img src="https://i.imgur.com/mlMGZTf.png" alt="https://i.imgur.com/mlMGZTf.png"></p>
<h2>Next Step: Copy to Clipboard</h2>
<p>Let's add some additional functionality to this app by allowing the user to copy a color to their clipboard. Be careful 🚧 You may come across</p>
<pre><code class="language-javascript">document.execCommand();
</code></pre>
<p>but this method is <strong>deprecated</strong>. The alternative to use is <a href="https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/API/Clipboard_API">Clipboard API</a>:</p>
<pre><code class="language-jsx">navigator.clipboard.writeText('text to copy');
</code></pre>
<p>Remember to change the style of the color divs so that it shows it can be clicked on (hint: cursor: pointer).</p>
<p>Now the tricky part is showing a message to the user that the color code has been copied to their clipboard. This message should only appear for a couple of seconds, and it will have to disappear. Here I used the setTimeout method that will hide the message after 2 seconds:</p>
<pre><code class="language-jsx">const showMessage = (id: string) => {
  // show message
  document.getElementById(id).setAttribute('style', 'display: block');
  navigator.clipboard.writeText(`#${id}`);
  // wait 1 sec
  // hide message
  setTimeout(() => {
    document.getElementById(id).setAttribute('style', 'display: none');
  }, 2000);
};
</code></pre>
<p>The <code>id</code> parameter is the HEX Color String and is included in each of the color divs:</p>
<pre><code class="language-html">&#x3C;p id="{color.hex}" className="color-box-copy">COPIED TO CLIPBOARD&#x3C;/p>
</code></pre>
<hr>
<h3>Live Color Generator: <a href="https://color-generator-drab.vercel.app/">https://color-generator-drab.vercel.app/</a></h3>
<h3>Find the code on GitHub: <a href="https://github.com/EzequielCaste/react-projects/tree/main/color-generator">color-generator</a></h3>
<p><img src="https://i.imgur.com/4ziuHGk.png" alt="https://i.imgur.com/4ziuHGk.png"></p>
<p>Good luck! 🥳</p>
<hr>
<h3>Credits &#x26; References</h3>
<p><a href="https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/API/Clipboard_API">https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/API/Clipboard_API</a></p>
<p><a href="https://noeldelgado.github.io/values.js/">https://noeldelgado.github.io/values.js/</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
  
    <item>
      <guid>http://ezecastellanos.com.ar/posts/Check your head 0bc2d019ba0e4a8a98ab5def8c090365</guid>
      <title>Check your <head></title>
      <description>What are meta tags and why are they important?</description>
      <link>http://ezecastellanos.com.ar/posts/Check your head 0bc2d019ba0e4a8a98ab5def8c090365</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jun 2021 05:35:07 GMT</pubDate>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1>Check your  🤔</h1>
<p>There are many steps to follow when designing and building a webpage, choosing a color scheme, determining which technologies to use, which hosting site, domain name, etc. That is why it is important to plan <em>before</em> you start writing any line of code. But sometimes we're in a hurry, we want to build a quick webpage and get it uploaded fast. This is where <strong>mistakes</strong> are made. Like the saying goes:</p>
<blockquote>
<p><em>errare humanum est</em></p>
</blockquote>
<p>To err is human, we as humans will make mistakes, it is better to plan ahead and prevent them in the first place. Sometimes we focus so much on the design and functionality of a website that we forget to check if our  contain the basic recommended  elements.</p>
<p>So what's the problem? No problem at all... This just goes to say that it's ok to make mistakes, we all do, Trainees. Juniors, Seniors and even those <strong><a href="https://media1.tenor.com/images/b3afd78db54dccbe7b3785e59dd45d3d/tenor.gif">LVL +9000</a></strong>. You're not the only one. Take a deep breath, relax, do some Google researching about the error, read some documentation or ask a fellow developer for help.</p>
<hr>
<p>Let's get back to the main topic of this post, checking your <strong></strong> so that it has all the right metadata.</p>
<h2>What are meta tags?</h2>
<p>Meta tags are fragments of text content that provide an outline or summary of the webpage. The  tag defines metadata about an HTML document. Metadata is data (information) about data.</p>
<h2>Why are meta tags important?</h2>
<p>The information provided in the meta tags will appear in search results and when someone shares a link to your site on social media or in chats.</p>
<h2>What metadata should you include?</h2>
<h3>Charset</h3>
<pre><code class="language-html">&#x3C;meta charset="utf-8" />
</code></pre>
<p>This element specifies the document's character encoding.</p>
<h3>Viewport</h3>
<pre><code class="language-html">&#x3C;meta name="viewport" content="width=device-width, initial-scale=1.0" />
</code></pre>
<p>The viewport is the user's visible area of a web page. Set the viewport to make your website look good on all devices.</p>
<h3>Title</h3>
<pre><code class="language-html">&#x3C;title>Ezequiel Castellanos | Front-end Developer&#x3C;/title>
</code></pre>
<p>The title element represents the title of the HTML document (not the content).</p>
<h3>Author &#x26; Description</h3>
<pre><code class="language-html">&#x3C;meta name="author" content="Ezequiel Castellanos" />
&#x3C;meta name="description" content="Personal website and Blog" />
</code></pre>
<p>These two elements specify the author and provide a brief description of the page.</p>
<hr>
<h2>Open Graph Protocol (og)</h2>
<p>Facebook invented the Open Graph protocol to provide more metadata for our websites to display when we share a link in social media. The link will now appear along with an image and description, much more captivating than a simple word link.</p>
<pre><code class="language-html">&#x3C;meta
  property="og:title"
  content="Ezequiel Castellanos | Front-end Developer"
/>
&#x3C;meta property="og:type" content="website" />
&#x3C;meta
  property="og:image"
  content="https://avatars.githubusercontent.com/u/51804994?s=400&#x26;amp;u=efe88c4acafeb4fe560f666482b1454dca508408&#x26;amp;v=4"
/>
&#x3C;meta property="og:url" content="https://ezecastellanos.com.ar" />

&#x3C;meta property="og:site_name" content="Ezequiel Castellanos" />
&#x3C;meta property="og:description" content="Personal Website and Blog" />
</code></pre>
<p><img src="/images/Check%20your%20head%200bc2d019ba0e4a8a98ab5def8c090365/Untitled.png" alt="Preview of how a link to a blog post would look like if posted on Facebook"><em>Preview of how a link to a blog post would look like if posted on Facebook</em></p>
<hr>
<h2>Twitter Cards</h2>
<p>Similar to Open Graph Data, Twitter Cards allows you to attach images and description to Tweets.</p>
<p>Whenever a user Tweets a link to your content, the tweet will include a “Card” that will be visible to their followers.</p>
<pre><code class="language-html">&#x3C;meta name="twitter:card" content="summary" />
&#x3C;meta name="twitter:site" content="@Ezequiel_Caste" />
&#x3C;meta name="twitter:creator" content="@Ezequiel_Caste" />
&#x3C;meta name="twitter:title" content="Ezequiel Castellanos" />
&#x3C;meta name="twitter:description" content="Personal Website and Blog" />
&#x3C;meta name="twitter:url" content="https://ezecastellanos.com.ar" />
&#x3C;meta
  name="twitter:image"
  content="https://avatars.githubusercontent.com/u/51804994?s=400&#x26;amp;u=efe88c4acafeb4fe560f666482b1454dca508408&#x26;amp;v=4"
/>
</code></pre>
<p><img src="/images/Check%20your%20head%200bc2d019ba0e4a8a98ab5def8c090365/Untitled%201.png" alt="Preview of a Twitter Card for a blog post"><em>Preview of a Twitter Card for a blog post</em></p>
<p>Once your twitter card tags are up and running you can use <a href="https://cards-dev.twitter.com/validator">this validator</a> to check-out how it would look. The validator checks for the correct tags and gives you this message if everything went ok:</p>
<pre><code class="language-javascript">INFO:  Page fetched successfully
INFO:  24 metatags were found
INFO:  twitter:card = summary tag found
INFO:  Card loaded successfully
</code></pre>
<hr>
<h2>Favicons</h2>
<p>This is the icon that will appear in the user's Bookmark or Favorites in their browser.</p>
<p>Adding your favicon to the  of your site:</p>
<pre><code class="language-html">&#x3C;link rel="shortcut icon" href="favicon.ico" type="image/x-icon" />
</code></pre>
<p>I highly recommend using <a href="https://realfavicongenerator.net/">https://realfavicongenerator.net/</a> you only have to upload the image you want to use as favicon and the site automatically generates the meta tags and provides a zip file with all the necessary icon files of different sizes.</p>
<p>Don't have a favicon yet? You can make your own icon with <a href="https://www.canva.com/">https://www.canva.com/</a> It's really easy, mine only took 10 minutes to design.</p>
<p><img src="/images/Check%20your%20head%200bc2d019ba0e4a8a98ab5def8c090365/Untitled%202.png" alt="Original design made with Canva"><em>Original design made with Canva</em></p>
<p><img src="/images/Check%20your%20head%200bc2d019ba0e4a8a98ab5def8c090365/Untitled%203.png" alt="Favicon appears to the left of your webpage title." title="TITLE"><em>Favicon appears to the left of your webpage title.</em></p>
<hr>
<h2>Check your </h2>
<p>Once you have your meta tags, open graph, twitter card and favicon included in your webpage, you can verify how the links to your site will appear in search engines and social media posts. Check your URL with this site:</p>
<p><a href="https://metatags.io/">Meta Tags - Preview, Edit and Generate</a></p>
<p>This site will also generate all the required meta tags in case you missed any.</p>
<p>Good luck! 🥳</p>
<hr>
<h3>Credits &#x26; References</h3>
<p><a href="https://www.w3schools.com/tags/tag_meta.asp">Meta Tag</a></p>
<p><a href="https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Learn/HTML/Introduction_to_HTML/The_head_metadata_in_HTML">The_head_metadata_in_HTML</a></p>
<p><a href="https://developer.twitter.com/en/docs/twitter-for-websites/cards/overview/markup">Twitter Cards</a></p>
<p><a href="https://ogp.me/">https://ogp.me/</a></p>
<p><a href="https://metatags.io/">https://metatags.io/</a></p>
<p><a href="https://realfavicongenerator.net/">https://realfavicongenerator.net/</a></p>
<p><a href="https://www.canva.com/">https://www.canva.com/</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
  
    <item>
      <guid>http://ezecastellanos.com.ar/posts/hello world</guid>
      <title>Hello World!</title>
      <description>Hello, good evening and welcome to The Middle of the Film. Actually, this is the beginning of my blog, the very first post ever! Having said that, Welcome!</description>
      <link>http://ezecastellanos.com.ar/posts/hello world</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Apr 2021 05:35:07 GMT</pubDate>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1>Hello World!</h1>
<p><img src="https://y.yarn.co/9ad103b2-da58-41dd-9270-e59ad61dba2e_screenshot.jpg" alt="Welcome!"></p>
<blockquote>
<p>Hello, good evening and welcome to The Middle of the Blog.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Actually, this is the beginning of my blog, the very first post ever! Having said that, Welcome!</p>
<h2>About me</h2>
<p>Hi there! My name is Ezequiel Castellanos and I'm a junior Front-end web developer and English/Spanish translator.</p>
<p>I enjoy making websites, drinking <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mate_(drink)">mate</a>, baking homemade pizza and bread, and also researching and learning about technology or science. When I'm not coding,</p>
<p>I started creating websites as a hobby and now I've realized this can be more than a hobby. So I started to teach myself <strong>HTML, CSS and JavaScript</strong>, thanks to the great developer community at freeCodeCamp. Currently learning more in depth <strong>React.js</strong>, <strong>Next.js</strong>, <strong>Tailwind CSS</strong> and <strong>SASS</strong>.</p>
<h2>The Blog</h2>
<p>This blog is a nice little fun project I'm building with the help of <a href="https://www.manuelobregozo.com/">Manuel Obregozo</a>. He's been helping me on my developer path with great advice and encouraging me to apply to as many jobs as possible. <strong>First Dev Job here I come!</strong> 🚀</p>
<p>The main idea of this site is to have a working blog and add updates and features in small increments. For a start, the blog is developed with Next.js and Tailwind CSS. I will try to detail all the challenges and obstacles that appear during the development of this blog. Stay tuned! 👋</p>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
  
      </channel>
    </rss>
  