
    <rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" version="2.0">
      <channel>
        <title>Ezequiel Castellanos | Front-end Developer</title>
        <link>http://ezecastellanos.com.ar</link>
        <description>Blog page for Ezequiel</description>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Jun 2021 13:07:45 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="http://ezecastellanos.com.ar" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        
    <item>
      <guid>http://ezecastellanos.com.ar/posts/site update</guid>
      <title>Updates to the Website!</title>
      <description>It's been three months since the website was created, it's time for some updates</description>
      <link>http://ezecastellanos.com.ar/posts/site update</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jun 2021 13:07:45 GMT</pubDate>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1>Time for Updates!</h1>
<p>Sometimes we forget</p>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
  
    <item>
      <guid>http://ezecastellanos.com.ar/posts/hello world</guid>
      <title>Hello World!</title>
      <description>Hello, good evening and welcome to The Middle of the Film. Actually, this is the beginning of my blog, the very first post ever! Having said that, Welcome!</description>
      <link>http://ezecastellanos.com.ar/posts/hello world</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Apr 2021 05:35:07 GMT</pubDate>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1>Hello World!</h1>
<p><img src="https://y.yarn.co/9ad103b2-da58-41dd-9270-e59ad61dba2e_screenshot.jpg" alt="Welcome!"></p>
<blockquote>
<p>Hello, good evening and welcome to The Middle of the Blog.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Actually, this is the beginning of my blog, the very first post ever! Having said that, Welcome!</p>
<h2>About me</h2>
<p>Hi there! My name is Ezequiel Castellanos and I'm a junior Front-end web developer and English/Spanish translator.</p>
<p>I enjoy making websites, drinking <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mate_(drink)">mate</a>, baking homemade pizza and bread, and also researching and learning about technology or science. When I'm not coding,</p>
<p>I started creating websites as a hobby and now I've realized this can be more than a hobby. So I started to teach myself <strong>HTML, CSS and JavaScript</strong>, thanks to the great developer community at freeCodeCamp. Currently learning more in depth <strong>React.js</strong>, <strong>Next.js</strong>, <strong>Tailwind CSS</strong> and <strong>SASS</strong>.</p>
<h2>The Blog</h2>
<p>This blog is a nice little fun project I'm building with the help of <a href="https://www.manuelobregozo.com/">Manuel Obregozo</a>. He's been helping me on my developer path with great advice and encouraging me to apply to as many jobs as possible. <strong>First Dev Job here I come!</strong> 🚀</p>
<p>The main idea of this site is to have a working blog and add updates and features in small increments. For a start, the blog is developed with Next.js and Tailwind CSS. I will try to detail all the challenges and obstacles that appear during the development of this blog. Stay tuned! 👋</p>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
  
      </channel>
    </rss>
  